Kenny Choo

1/22 Shakespeare Grove, Heidelberg Heights, Victoria, Australia kenny_choo@yahoo.com +61 466 149 336

Career Summary

More than 20 years' experience in Product Management in Core Network (CS/PS/SDM) and Telco Cloud Solutions (NFV, overview of VMWare and Openstack).

Deployed the first Home Subscriber Server (HSS) on Cloud, on top of VMWare hypervisor.

Established overall strategy for delivering sales tools and collateral to the field for sales engagements, which covers email, social media, events, advertising on buses, train stations and billboards, etc.

Strong organization skills and can develop and roll out a successful on time, including End user marketing's go-to-market process

Systematic and good at keeping track of complex schedules, therefore task completion on time

Programming of work rollout on new products, from conceptualization to testing, within the given calendar planning cycles.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

- Marketing planning
- Account Management
- Sales Management
- Forecasting and Planning
- Consultative Selling

- Product Development
- Cross functional coordination
- Technical Writing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

01/2018- Present

Nokia Networks, Melbourne, AU

Customer Product Manager

- Direct interface with account team's market unit and customers
- Representing Technical Lead for Key opportunity
- Influencing customers on Nokia solution value proposition and driving the opportunity with the account teams
- Driving all pre-sales technical engagement from customer influencing, POC requirements, RFx responses to final solutions document

01/2014- 12/2017

Nokia Networks, Sydney, AU

Product Manager

- **Product demonstrations** for software and hardware
- Work together with account team to identify ways to attract and persuade prospective buyers
- Maintain good understanding of competitor's products and solutions offering
- Good understanding of current solution range, and future product roadmap
- Provide input on customer's requirement to Product Management team in headquarter
- Establish a long term relationship to technical and strategic decision makers of dedicated customers as agreed with Account Manager
- **Identify the customer business enablers** and develop the customer target architecture together with the customer
- **Cost and Margin optimization** of the customer solutions together with pricing manager (maximize customer and Nokia value)

08/2010-10/2013

U Mobile, Kuala Lumpur, MY

Senior Manager for Product Development

- Introduces, demonstrates, and promotes all new and current products
- Develop clear business requirement for new product & services for U Mobile
- Develop business case with Sales Department and Business Planning Team
- Manage cross functional team in development of product & services
- Work closely with Marketing Communications to plan for appropriate materials that support the growth of the trade
- Acquires knowledge of competitors' goods and services, and market conditions, develops features and services that are relevant to improve subscribers' affinity with U Mobile.
- Prepare productivity reports and maintaining and submitting records of business expenses.

02/2006-05/2010

Nokia Siemens Networks, Kuala Lumpur, MY

Core Solutions Manager

- Provide expert sales support to Celcom Account Team and also Customer Teams in Asia North to ensure the implementation and success of NSN's Core Network Solutions.
- Provide support for pricing, configuration and ordering of equipment.
- Influences technical mindset of the customer and RFx content via regular technical and road-map workshops
- Solution lead for Circuit and Packet Network area of responsibility when responding to RFx's
- Keeps abreast of knowledge on GSM/WCDMA/LTE/SAE, Circuit Switching and Packet Core Solutions (IMS, SA/DPI and PCRF), O& M support (FM, PM and CM, Nokia NetAct)
- Provides support on presentations to potential customers on product information.
- Develops clear and effective written proposals or quotations for current and prospective customers.

06/2004-01/2006

Huawei Technologies, Kuala Lumpur, MY

Product Manager

- Provides support for South East Asia to establish and act on selling opportunities.
- Develops professional relationships with customers to encourage customer loyalty and increase assigned account sales.
- Responsible for planning Radio and Core Dimensioning.
- Reports to sales management on sales made as well as the marketability of goods and services.
- Oversees and prepares product presentations at conferences for Huawei.
- Assists in preparation of quotations and project or proposals and follow up as needed.

11/2000-05/2004

Siemens Ltd., Bangkok, TH

Technical Project Consultant

- Knowledge on GSM Circuit Core. Worked also on Operations and Maintenance products
- To provide technical support during acquisition (presentations, discussions, strategic guidance)
- To provide technical preparation of tenders (presentations, negotiations)
- To provide project support & customer care (Application Product System Ordering process, negotiation of network integration)
- To prepare technical task (product planning issues, project Feature Request)
- To manage/support ongoing projects to the local sales offices during project implementation (distribution of information, project strategy)

06/1997-10/2000 NTT MSC, Kuala Lumpur, MY

IT Consultant

- To manage corporate accounts and to consult potential customers & propose IT
- To manage projects in project tendering & technical design
- To explore new market segment for Frame Relay and Internet service
- To conduct user training session

EDUCATION & LEARNING

VolTE Sales Guidance, Sydney - 2017 **VoLTE and VoWiFi Market Overview, Sydney – 2017** 3G Core Evolution, Sydney - 2017 Subscriber Data Management Level 3 CO Sales Certificate, Sydney - 2016 Nokia Cloud Solutions for Core Network, Sydney - 2016 Anti Corruption Compliance Training 2015, Sydney - 2016 APJ Core Bootcamp, Bangkok – 2016 Competition Law, Sydney - 2016 I Own Quality, Sydney - 2016 Core Telco Cloud, Sydney – 2015 Ethical Business Training, Sydney - 2015 Information Security in Nokia, Sydney - 2015 Smart Tendering, Sydney - 2015

I Own Quality, Sydney - 2016

Lean Six Sigma for Beginners, Sydney - 2014

Understanding Customer Perceived Value, Sydney - 2014

Customer Service Fundamentals: Building Rapport in Customer Relationships, Sydney - 2014

Project Management Training - Managing By Project, Kuala Lumpur - 2012

Managerial and Leadership Skills Training, Kuala Lumpur - 2012

Diploma License to Sell, Singapore - 2007

The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People, Kuala Lumpur - 2007

Bachelor Degree of Electrical Engineering (Hons) - 1997

University Technology Malaysia, Johor Bahru, MY

LANGUAGE

Language Spoken : English, Mandarin, Malay Language Written : English, Chinese, Malay

References upon Request